David Dangerfield

Summary

- Lead Software Developer with 20 yrs experience (14 backend, 6 frontend)
- Specializes in frontend development
- Expert in Vue.js and experienced in React and Angular
- Speaker at local conferences and meetups

BIO:

David has been developing software for over 20 years, focusing solely on front-end since 2014. His strong foundation in computer science, good real-world experience, and passion for staying current, make him a compelling addition to any org. He enjoys attending/speaking at software conferences workshops and meetups. While his current focus is front-end development, past roles have given him broad experience in back-end, test, and deployment automation.

Experience



💆 Senior Frontend Engineer

SmugMug

Sep 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months +) Helping build and maintain smugmug.com:D We host "billions of happy photos"

and boast "millions of passionate customers".

Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, GraphQL, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Git, GitHub, Jenkins, Jira, Visual Studio Code, Slack, and a Kanban methodology with continuous integration & deployment.



Senior Frontend Developer/Consultant

David A. Dangerfield

Jan 2018 - Present (2 years 10 months +)

Providing limited consulting and services for frontend software projects in the Vue.js ecosystem.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, Vuex, GraphQL, Nuxt.js, Cypress, Jest, Jira, Jenkins, Vuetify, Material Design, Git, etc.



Lead Frontend Developer / Architect, IBM Services

IBM Services

Jan 2018 - Aug 2018 (8 months)

Led the front-end development of a web app to view and update company financial and contractual information.

Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REST, Angular (v5), Angular Material, Git, Git Town, ZenHub, Visual Studio Code, Slack.



FED@IBM Rochester Branch co-founder/co-leader

IBM Services

Dec 2017 - Aug 2018 (9 months)

Co-founded and led the front-end developer group at IBM Rochester. It aims to foster front-end developer cohesion in Rochester, MN. Meetings help people level-up on the latest in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js and UI/UX.

- attend and publicize tech talks every other week
- encourage members to volunteer to give talks
- give talks myself as needed
- encourage attendance by non-IBM community professionals



Frontend (UI) Developer, Watson Health Consulting Services

IBM Services

Nov 2015 - Dec 2017 (2 years 2 months)

Developed custom cognitive web/mobile applications for clients in the healthcare industry and beyond. Focused on front-end work.

Sep '17 - Dec '17: Developed cognitive, web app to improve efficiency for the call center of a top 50 US bank. Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, Vuex, Github.

May '17 - Aug '17: Developed cognitive web app to assist IBM sales professionals. Implemented responsive design (iPhone5 to desktop) with HTML CSS and JavaScript. Used Vue.js, Vuex (i.e. Flux architecture a la Redux) Bluemix (IBM Cloud hosting), Webpack, Google Analytics, Github Enterprise

Jan '17 - Apr '17: Developed cognitive web app to assist pharmaceutical researchers in drug development. (A customization of IBM Watson for Drug Discovery). Implemented UI designs with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Used AngularJS & Visual Studio Code. Led small team of UI developers. https://www.ibm.com/us-en/marketplace/ibm-watson-for-drug-discovery

Dec '16 - Feb '17: Developed Watson cognitive business intelligence web app for business consultants. Implemented UI with HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Used AngularJS 1.5 components.

Oct '16 - Nov '16: Developed rough prototype web app for healthcare workers to visualize health issues on a map of the human body. Used D3.js, three.js (3D lib) and Angular (aka Angular2) with angular-cli

Apr '16 - Sept '16: Developed iPad and desktop web app to assist healthcare workers quickly digest patient history and system recommendations for diabetes treatment. Implemented responsive designs using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Used similar technologies to prior role.

Nov '15 - Feb '16: Developed mobile-first web app to engage and inform healthcare consumers and improve compliance. Implemented responsive designs using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Developed an AngularJS component generator to make boilerplate easy. Used: AngularJS 1.5 components, Karma + Jasmine unit testing, Protractor e2e test, ES6, Babel, Gulp, JSPM, Sublime Text

Senior Web Application Developer

Preventice Solutions

Aug 2013 - Oct 2015 (2 years 3 months)

May 2014 - Oct. 2015: UI development on multitenant cloud-based web application for the healthcare industry. Implemented ability to login as multi-role user then change role without re-login.

ASP.NET MVC with Razor views, C#, Javascript, JQuery, JQueryUI, claims-based authorization (SAML), seamless integration with legacy ASP.NET WebForms app, all calling into Web API services app

Jan. 2014 - Apr. 2014: Platform development in support of BodyGuardian remote patient monitoring system. Built Notification Service that ran as a Windows service and consumed messages on ActiveMQ. Built web services to return data for user groups and care teams.

ASP.NET Web API RESTful services, C#, Ling to Entities, ActiveMQ, MS SQL Server, MacOS, VMware Fusion, Windows 8, Agile methods

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2013: Backend Java development on custom web applications for clients in the healthcare industry. Built web services to CRUD patient healthcare protocols (Java, Tomcat, MSSQL). Automated integration test suite (JUnit). Researched and added code coverage analysis to build (EclEmma - JaCoCo).

Chosen by management as a mentor for new team members.

Prior roles were at IBM. Details available upon request...

Education



Purdue University

MS, Computer Science 2000 - 2002



Brigham Young University

BS, Computer Science 1997 - 2000

Skills

JavaScript • HTML • CSS • Vue.js • Nuxt.js

Honors & Awards



Lab Services Award: Sharing Expertise (Individual award) - IBM

Sep 2017

Solutions Lab Services Award - Given for demonstrating the IBM Practice: "Share expertise"



HCLS Champions (team award) - IBM global leadership

Dec 2017

For my work on a customization of IBM Watson for Drug Discovery, myself and the entire 10-person development team were recognized by IBM leadership as people who:

- Exemplify our culture of health and high performance and
- Produce meaningful experiences and outcomes for clients



IBM Manager's Choice Award (1H 2018): Sharing Expertise (Individual Award) - IBM

Jun 2018

For taking the initiative to speak at conferences and meetups about frontend development technologies.